

340, Mokdongseo-ro, Yangcheon-gu, Seoul, 08089, Republic of Korea

□ (+82) 10-9686-8177 | ■ tyoung96@naver.com | ★ taeyoung96.github.io | □ Taeyoung96

"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."

Summary.

This is Taeyoung Kim, who wants to become an autonomous driving or robotics SW engineer. My research interests are Computer Vision and SLAM. I like to take on challenging tasks and I like to grow up with my colleagues around me. That's why I record and share what I did on my Github or Technical Blog. I would like to participate in changing the world with advanced science and technology.

Research Interests

Computer Vision Object Detection, Segmentation, Depth Estimation

SLAM Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry

Education _____

Kwang Woon University Seoul, S.Korea

B.S. IN SCHOOL OF ROBOTICS

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022 (Expected)

- Current GPA: 4.07 / 4.50, Current Major GPA: 4.50 / 4.50
- Club: BARAM (Robotics Academic Group) [2020 Staff], DAISY (English Conversation Club) [2019 Spring President]

Work Experience_

Computer Vision Lab @Korea Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

UNDERGRADUATE LAB INTERN (ADVISOR: PROF. SANGPIL KIM) · Research on computer vision using an Event camera Mar. 2021 - Present

KIST(Korea Institute of Science and Technology)

Seoul, S.Korea

STUDENT INTERN (ADVISOR: DR. KANGGEON KIM)

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Research on Monocular Depth Estimation
- Participated in KIST disinfect robot (AI Disinfection Robot) project [Video]

Image Process System Lab @Kwang Woon Univ

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Lab Intern (Advisor: Prof. Donggyu Sim)

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Research on Image Processing based on Deep learning
- · Participated in seminars related to Deep Learning and Image Processing

Publication

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE

UR2021, Taeyoung Kim, Omer Faruk Ince, JongBeom Baek, Jun-Sik Kim, KangGeon Kim, 2021.7

"Dense Monocular SLAM applied Depth Estimation"

KROS

DOMESTIC CONFERENCE

KROS2021, Taeyoung Kim, TaeHwan Kim, GiJae Lee, KangGeon Kim, 2021.5

KROS

"Recognition of disinfection targets and generation of semantic map for disinfection robot"

KSPC2020, Naseong Kwon, Taeyoung Kim, Subin Kim, Joohyung Byeon, Jongsuk Lee, Donggyu Sim, 2020.9 "Luma Mapping with Chroma Scaling based on CNN feature map for VVC subjective quality improvement"

IEIE

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

2020.11	Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
2020.9	5th Place on B-track , Korea Health Datathon 2020	NAVER CLOUD
		PLATFORM
2019.10	Dean's List , for Academic Excellence	KwangWoon Univ.
HONORS	•	

Honors

2021	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship,	Korea Student Aid
	for the students with excellent grades, those who have been recommended by the university	Foundation
2020	National Science and Engineering Undergraudate Scholarship ,	Korea Student Aid
	for the students with excellent grades, those who have been recommended by the university	Foundation
2019-2	Full tuition Scholarship, for Top seat last semester	KwangWoon Univ.

Skills____

Programming C++/C, Python, JAVA, Matlab **Framework** Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras

DevOps Git, Docker, ROS **Languages** Korean, English

Extracurricular Activity

Technical BlogsGithub blog

WRITERS May. 2020 - Present

- Writing some posts about lecture summary, paper review, some tips for developments.
- To share what I have studied with others and to remember it longer.

Monocular Depth Estimation with ORB-SLAM2

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

Sep. 2020 - Nov. 2020

PERSONAL TOY PROJECT

I was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model.

- i was curious about the performance of the recent depth estimation model
- I used 'Monocular Depth Estimation with Transfer Learning pretrained MobileNetV2' model and applied to ORB-SLAM2
 also compared with ORB-SLAM2(Monocular mode), ORB-SLAM2(RGB-D mode)
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].

KCCV 2020 Korea computer vision society

,

• Participated to know about the trend of Computer Vision

Using deep learning for data analysis and image processing (Basic)

Korea open source software

Jul. 2020

Aug. 2020

• Studied lectures which is related to the using Deep learning framework(Keras)

Runner Alarm System based on Deep Learning

BARAM (Robotics Academic Group)

Personal Toy Project Apr. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- I wanted to distinguish between walking children and running children with an object detection model.
- When children are running for an amount of time, a beep sounds.
- The source code related to this toy project is on my [Github repository].